John T. McCutcheon Papers
John T. McCutcheon Papers
1895-1947
McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949
10.83 linear ft.
Papers of the American political cartoonist and war correspondent including over 600 original cartoons, writings, biographical material, published material and a scrapbook of clippings from World War I.
149159
Biographical History
John T. McCutcheon (1870-1949) was an American cartoonist and war correspondent who worked for the Chicago Tribune for over 40 years.
John Tinney McCutcheon was born on a small farm several miles south of Lafayette in Tippecanoe County, Indiana on May 6, 1870. He spent his early childhood on the farm and his youth in neighboring communities. After receiving a B.S. degree from Purdue University in 1889, he joined the staff of the Chicago Morning News as an artist.
During 1892 and 1893, McCutcheon covered the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago and in 1895 he first traveled to Europe. The presidential election of 1896 between Republican William McKinley and Democrat William Jennings Bryan provided McCutcheon with the material to open his career as a political cartoonist. While traveling abroad, the Spanish-American War got underway and McCutcheon served as a war correspondent in the Philippines returning home several year later after the Boer War.
After returning to the United States, McCutcheon started working on his first serial cartoons including Bird Center and in 1903 he joined the Chicago Tribune for whom he contributed editorial cartoons, illustrations and feature stories. During the first years of World War I, McCutcheon reported from Europe.
McCutcheon continued to travel extensively. He purchased his own island, Salt Cay in 1916 and went on hunting trips with several U.S. generals. He made several trips around the world and in 1909-1910 he spent over four months in Africa on a big game hunt, all the while contributing articles to the Chicago Tribune.
McCutcheon's cartoons ran the gamut from presidential races and national politics to societal changes and economic hardships. He published illustrations in magazines such as Cosmopolitan and illustrated several books by George Ade, a fellow Indianan and Purdue graduate whose humorous "fables" were popular from the late nineteenth century through the 1930s. His illustrations were also used by several railroads. McCutcheon's autobiography, Drawn from Memory, was published posthumously in 1950.
Purdue University and Notre Dame awarded him honorary doctoral degrees in 1926 and 1931 respectively and McCutcheon also lectured throughout the United States. His cartoons earned him an international reputation and he received a Pulitzer Prize for his 1931 cartoon, "A Wise Economist Asks a Question." He was a member of the Royal Geographical Society of London, the Chicago Zoological Society (of which he served as president for over twenty years), the University Players and Coffee House of New York, the Military Order of Carabao and the Society of Manila Bay of Washington.
Following serious illness, McCutcheon retired from the Chicago Tribune in 1946. John T. McCutcheon died June 10, 1949 in Lake Forest, Illinois. His son, Shaw McCutcheon is an editorial cartoonist.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John T. McCutcheon Papers are divided into five series containing both visual and textual works by McCutcheon as well as biographical information.
Cartoons contains a total of approximately 663 original editorial cartoons (circa 1904-1945) drawn by McCutcheon for the Chicago Tribune as well as two copies. There are 254 dated cartoons. Within the 409 undated cartoons there are approximately 155 items with captions and approximately 254 items without captions.
Of particular interest are two copies of McCutcheon's 1931 cartoon, "A Wise Economist Asks the Question" which won the Pulitzer Prize. Topical subject matter receiving frequent attention by McCutcheon includes World War I and its aftermath (particularly Europe’s war debt), the implementation of the income tax in 1913, the increasing pervasiveness of Henry Ford’s automobile, the decision to join the League of Nations and the Mexican Revolution. While focusing primarily on national and world politics, McCutcheon also documented changes to Chicago’s political and physical landscape in terms of building projects and transportation. Recurring themes include “The Changing World” which compared the past to the present and “Cartoons of the Day” in which McCutcheon divided the image into three separate cartoons.
McCutcheon worked primarily with pen and ink on illustration board and paper but crayon was also used. Captions and pre-production notes with special instructions appear in pen and pencil. McCutcheon frequently wrote extensive text and subtitles on the back of the cartoons. Dimensions vary, although most are at least 14 ½" x 18 ½".
Illustrations and Drawings (1895-1947) includes original artwork and reproductions of McCutcheon's work. Many of these original pieces appeared in Cosmopolitan and others were drawn to accompany serialized stories. Some are pencil drawings. The reproductions include a color railroad dinner menu, work for the Illinois Children's Home and Aid Society and a rough composite of sketches and text reporting on events in the U.S. Senate. Also of interest is a copy of a map McCutcheon drew of the island he purchased.
Biographical material contains three photographs of McCutcheon, his autograph, typed biographies and programs from events he attended.
Writings consists of a diary from 1898 and undated class notes.
Published material (1902-1944) includes copies of articles written by McCutcheon; newspaper clippings of his articles, illustrated features and color artwork that appeared in the Chicago Tribune; as well as a scrapbook with McCutcheon's World War I reporting and drawings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Dated cartoons are arranged chronologically. Undated cartoons are arranged in alphabetical order by caption where one is present.
Related Material
See the
Shaw McCutcheon Cartoons
for material related to John T. McCutcheon's son.
has collections of more than 150 cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
A number of published items have been removed from the collection, cataloged and sent to Rare Books. Please see the inventory for more information.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; McCutcheon, John T. (John Tinney), 1870-1949.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Democratic Party (U.S.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Indiana Society of Chicago.; League of Nations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Chicago tribune.; Cosmopolitan (London, England); A Boy in Spring-Time.; A Boy in Summer-Time.; A Boy in Fall-Time.; A Boy in Winter-Time.; Agriculture -- Caricatures and cartoons.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Boxing -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- Illinois -- Chicago.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Editorial cartoons -- Illinois -- Chicago.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Great Depression -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Industries -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Journalists -- United States.; Prohibition -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Political corruption -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Strikes and lockouts -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Travel.; Treaty of Versailles (1919) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; War correspondents -- United States.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1900-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Europe -- History--1871-1918 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Europe -- History -- 1918-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Mexico -- History -- Revolution, 1910-1920 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Chicago (Ill.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Articles.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Drawings (visual works); Diaries.; Editorial cartoons.; Illustrations.; Printed materials (object genre); Scrapbooks.; Cartoonists.; Journalists.; War correspondents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. John T. McCutcheon, 1964.
Inventory
- Cartoons, 665 items; Click here for a detailed inventory.
  - Dated, includes 2 copies of an original cartoon; 256 items
    - 12 Jan 1908, 9 May 1922, 4 Feb 1923, 1908 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - 1925 Jan, 1925 Jul - Oct (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    - 1925 Nov - Dec (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    - 1926 Jan, 1926 May - Jun (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    - 1926 Jul - Sep (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
    - 1926 Oct - Dec (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
    - 1927 Jan, 1927 Apr - Jul (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
    - 1927 Aug - Nov (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
    - 1928 Jan, 1928 May - Aug, 1928 Nov - Dec (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
    - 1929 Jan - Feb, 1929 Jul - Dec (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
    - 1929 (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    - 1930 Jan - Feb, 1930 Apr, 1930 Jun, 1930 Sep - Nov (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    - 1931 Jun, 1931 Aug, 1931 Oct, includes two copies of McCutcheon's 1931 cartoon, "A Wise Economist Asks the Question" (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
    - 1933 Jul, 1933 Sep - Dec (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    - 1934 Jun - Sep (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    - 1935 Jan, 1935 May (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    - 1936 Apr, 1936 Jun - Dec (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    - 1937 Mar, 1937 Jul - Nov (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    - 1938 Feb, 1938 Aug - Sep,1938 Nov (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    - 1939 Feb,1939 Apr, 1939 Jul - Oct (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
    - 1940 Mar, 1940 May, 1940 Jul - Aug, 1940 Dec (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    - 1941 Jan, 1941 Sep - Oct (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    - 1942 Mar, 1942 Sep - Oct, 1942 Dec (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - 1943 Jan, 1943 May,1943 Aug, 1943 Dec (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
    - 1944 Jan - Feb, 1944 Jul, 1944 Sep (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
    - 1945 Mar (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
  - Undated, 409 items
    - A (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
    - B-C (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
    - D-F (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
    - G-H (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
    - I-L (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
    - M, circa 1912; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
    - N-O, circa 1900-1921; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
    - P-R, circa 1924; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
    - S, circa 1904-1913; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
    - T, circa 1916; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
    - W, circa 1909-1913; undated (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
    - W, undated (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
    - W, undated (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 6, Folder 7)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 7)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
    - Untitled, undated (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
- Illustrations and drawings
  - Original artwork
    - "An Heir at Large", 10 Jul; 27 Aug,; 3 Dec; 3 items (Oversize 8)
    - Cosmopolitan - color artwork, undated; 5 items (Oversize 8)
    - Cosmopolitan- "Happy Endings", 1923; 4 items (Oversize 8)
    - Cosmopolitan- "O'Malley article", 1920; 4 items (Oversize 8)
    - Cosmopolitan- "Vacations Then", 1924 Sep; 2 items (Oversize 8)
    - Cosmopolitan- other artwork, 1925-1926; 3 items (Oversize 8)
    - "Crossed Wires", 1926; 7 items (Oversize 8)
    - "Hints", 1925; 13 items (Oversize 8)
    - Indiana Society picnic at Cedar Lake, undated (Oversize 8)
    - "Mr. J. Raglan Patchmore", 1931; 2 items (Oversize 8)
    - "Mr. Lugubrious Blue and Mr. Smiley Gladd", 1920; 1925,; undated; 3 items (Oversize 8)
    - Drawings, 17 Feb 1899; 1899 Jul,; 2 items (Box 1)
      "Burmese Girl"
      "Maria's Cousin"
    - "Stories of the Streets and of the Town", 1895-1897; 14 items (Box 1)
    - "What a Man Sees Who Goes Away from Home" by George Ade, 1895; related to Ade and McCutcheon's first trip abroad; 24 items (Box 1)
    - Ink drawings and illustrations, undated; 3 items (Oversize 8)
      "The Ocean Liner of the Future"
      "Dooley"
      "Senator Fairbanks"
    - Untitled ink drawings and illustrations, 1930; undated; 5 items (Oversize 8)
    - Untitled drawings and illustrations, 1926; undated; 4 items (Oversize 8)
  - Prints and reproductions
    - Dinner Menu- Burlington Route, 1947 (Box 1)
    - Illinois Children's Home and Aid Society Ballet Benefit, 1938 (Oversize 8)
    - McCutcheon's Cartoons on Post Cards and Hangers, 1903; 1905 (Box  1)
      A Boy in Spring-Time
      A Boy in Summer-Time
      A Boy in Fall-Time
      A Boy in Winter-Time
    - Mr. Harriman's Plans for Reorganizing the Railways of the Country, circa 1909 (Oversize 8)
    - Photograph of art inscribed to Howard Gillette, circa 1907 (Box 1)
    - Reprints, undated; 5 items (Box 1)
    - Reproductions, circa 1905; circa 1907,; 1929,; 1935,; 1940; 8 items (Oversize 8)
      The Model Wife
      The Model Husband
      Two Ways of Looking at Things
      A Boy in the Springtime
      A Boy in Summertime
      When a Boy First Discovers the Enchanted Wonderland within Book Covers
      Consolation for the Discouraged
      The Enchanted City
    - The Romance of City Real Estate, circa 1925 (Oversize 8)
    - Treasure Island map by McCutcheon, undated; map of the island McCutcheon purchased in 1916 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Senate, 7 Dec 1926; 8 Dec 1926; drawings and written account; 2 items (Oversize 8)
- Biographical material
  - Autograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box 1)
  - Indiana Society of Chicago, 1910; 1938,; 1940; These items have been removed and sent to Rare Books. See below for a list of items.
    Sixth Annual Banquet
    Invitation to Twenty-Seventh Annual Banquet
    Twenty-Ninth Annual Banquet
  - Newspaper Artists Baseball game poster, undated (Oversize 8)
  - Photographs of McCutcheon, undated; 3 items (Oversize 8)
  - Sigma Chi Dinner programs, 1934; 1937; 2 items (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Diary, 1898; 12 typed pages (Box 1)
  - School notes, undated; includes notes on "Linear Perspective" (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books, These items have been removed and sent to Rare Books. See below for a list of items. (Box 1)
    Cartoons by McCutcheon (1903)
    Dawes Arboretum (1928)
    Indiana Society of Chicago series (9 volumes)
    Love Sonnets of an Office Boy (1904)
    To enter the wars now raging in Europe, Asia and Africa would be an act of national folly from which our country must be spared! ([1940])
    Yellowstone Park and how it was named ([1892])
  - Magazine articles by McCutcheon
    - "Address commemorating the Centenary of Mark Twain's Birth" in Revived Remarks on Mark Twain, 1936; item removed, cataloged and located in Rare Books (Box 1)
    - "The Battle of Manila Bay" from U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, undated (Box 1)
    - "Doing the Grand Canyon" from U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, 1909; item removed and located in Rare Books (Box 1)
    - "Famous Artist Speaks at Banquet of Greek Editors" from Banta's Greek Exchange, 1934 (Box 1)
    - "General Dawes" from The Century Magazine, 1928 May (Box 1)
    - "How Cartoons are Drawn" from The Writer, circa 1901 (Box 1)
    - "Ingomar in the Provinces" from South Shore Country Club, 1918 Jan (Box 1)
    - "The New Zoo" from The Chicago Visitor, 1931 Jan (Box 1)
    - "Taking the Right Turn" from Demcourier, 1939 (Box 1)
    - "Up the Andes and Down the Amazon" from The Trib, 1929 Jun
  - Magazine illustrations, 1908; 1926,; 1929-1930,; undated; from Collier's, College Humor, Purdue Alumnus, Liberty (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Articles by McCutcheon, 30 Jun 1929; 29 Oct 1944 (Box 1)
    - Chicago Tribune clippings, 1917; 1933,; 1937-1938,; 1941,; 1943-1944; most items are in color (Oversize 9)
    - Chicago Tribune graphic section clippings, 22 Oct 1933; 12 Nov 1933,; 24 Dec 1933,; 31 Dec 1933,; 7 Jan 1934,; 24 Jan 1934; 18 Feb 1934,; 2 Jan 1944; items are in color (Oversize 9)
    - Color features by McCutcheon
      - "Cruise of the Sun Dog", undated (Oversize 9)
      - "Famous Pirate Stronghold", 9 Jun 1912 (Oversize 9)
      - "Morgan's Bluff", 1912; undated (Oversize 9)
    - "Crossed Wires", 1926; Sunday feature in the Chicago Tribune (Oversize 9)
    - "Pipe Dreamers", 28 Sep 1902; 21 Sep 1902,; 7 Dec 1902 (Oversize 9)
    - Scrapbook, 1914; 1918-1919; clippings of McCutcheon’s World War I reporting and drawings (Oversize 9)
  - "So Lonesome for a Letter", undated; song inspired by McCutcheon cartoon; This item has been removed and sent to Rare Books. (Box 1)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
African-Americans B5F1 B7F9
Agricultural Adjustment Administration B3F2
animal cruelty B7F3
anti-trust laws B5F7 B7F3
armed forces B1F5 B3F6-B3F7 B4F3 B5F1-B5F3 B7F1 B7F6 B1F7-B1F8
Asia B6F2 B7F3
Austria B3F1 B3F3 B3F11 B5F1
automobile industry B1F4 B1F6-B1F7 B4F1 B4F4 B7F6
automobiles B1F2-B1F4 B1F8 B3F4 B6F1 B7F4
aviation B1F2 B1F7-B2F2 B3F4 B5F3 B6F1 B7F2 B7F4
Balkan Peninsula B1F5 B7F2
banking industry B1F6 B2F6-B2F7 B3F10 B7F9
Belgium B2F2-B2F3 B6F7-B7F1
Borah, William B3F3
Brazil B4F4
Britain B1F4 B1F7-B2F6 B3F1 B3F3-B3F7 B3F11 B4F1-B4F3 B4F5-B5F1 B5F3-B5F5 B6F1 B6F3-B6F5 B6F7-B7F2 B7F4-B7F8
Bryan, William Jennings B4F2 B4F4 B5F1 B5F4 B6F1-B6F2 B6F4 B7F1 B7F6 B7F9
Bulgaria B1F2
business B2F2 B2F4 B3F3-B3F4 B5F6 B6F2 B7F3
Caillaux, Joseph B1F2
California B5F6
Canada B5F4
Carranza, Emilio B2F1 B4F5
celebrities B1F6
censorship B7F2
charity B2F7 B4F4 B7F5
Chicago B1F1-B1F2 B1F5-B1F6 B1F8 B2F2 B2F4 B2F6 B6F3 B6F6-B6F7 B7F2 B7F5-B7F6 B7F8
Chicago School Board B1F1 B1F8
child labor B7F9
China B1F7 B2F3 B3F5 B4F1 B5F4 B7F1
Churchill, Winston B3F10 B3F12
Civil War B4F3
college students B1F6 B2F7 B4F5 B7F7
Colombia B5F5
communism B2F7 B6F3
Congress B1F2 B1F4-B1F6 B2F1 B2F3-B2F4 B2F6 B3F1-B3F2 B3F7 B3F9 B4F2-B4F3 B4F5 B5F3 B5F6-B5F7 B6F2 B6F4 B7F1-B7F3 B7F5-B7F7
construction B2F2 B3F2
consumers B3F1 B6F5
Coolidge, Calvin B1F2-B1F3 B1F5-B1F6 B2F2-B2F3 B3F1 B5F3 B6F1-B6F4 B7F4 B7F6
corruption B1F5-B1F7 B2F1 B2F7 B5F2 B6F1-B6F2 B6F4 B6F6 B7F2 B7F8-B7F9
Cox, James M. B4F2 B4F4 B7F1 B7F7-B7F8
credit B1F3 B2F4
crime B1F2-B1F3 B1F5-B1F6 B2F1 B5F7-B6F1 B6F3 B7F4
Cuba B4F4
Czechoslovakia B3F5-B3F6 B3F11
daylight savings time B1F6
de Gaulle, Charles B3F10
democracy B1F8 B3F5-B3F6 B6F2 B7F3
Democratic National Convention B1F1
Democratic Party B1F5 B2F1 B3F1 B3F3 B3F7 B4F2-B4F3 B4F5-B5F1 B5F3 B6F2-B6F3 B6F7-B7F1 B7F3 B7F6-B7F9
Dempsey, Jack B1F5 B3F1 B4F5 B7F7
Dever, William Emmett B1F4
Diaz, Adolfo B1F7
diseases B2F7
draft B3F7
economy B5F6 B6F6
Edison, Thomas B3F4
elections B1F4-B1F6 B2F1 B2F4 B2F6 B3F3 B3F5 B3F11 B5F1 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4 B6F7 B7F3-B7F4 B7F7
entertainment B1F3 B1F7
Europe B2F7 B3F5 B4F1 B4F5 B6F6 B7F3 B7F9
Farley, James B3F1
farming B1F4 B1F6 B1F8-B2F2 B3F1-B3F2 B3F4 B3F10 B5F3 B6F3 B6F5-B6F6 B7F4 B7F8-B7F9
fashion B2F2 B6F2 B6F5 B7F8
Finland B3F3 B3F6 B3F11
Ford, Henry B1F4 B2F7 B3F4 B7F4
France B1F2-B1F5 B2F2-B2F6 B3F3 B3F6 B3F11 B5F1 B5F3-B5F4 B5F6 B6F2-B7F2 B7F5-B7F7
Germany B1F3 B1F5 B2F2-B2F3 B2F6 B3F4-B3F6 B3F11-B4F1 B4F4-B5F1 B5F3-B5F5 B5F7 B6F2-B6F4 B6F6-B6F7 B7F2-B7F3 B7F5-B7F7
Ghandi, Mahatma B2F4
Giraud, Henri B3F10
gold B2F7
Gray, George B5F4
Great Depression B2F4-B2F5 B2F7-B3F1 B3F5 B6F3
Greece B1F2 B4F2 B5F5 B6F3 B6F5-B6F7 B7F5 B7F7
Haller, Stanislaw B1F4
Harding, Warren G. B4F2 B4F4 B5F4 B6F3-B6F4 B6F6
Harrison, Benjamin B7F7
Hauptmann, Bruno B3F2
Hearst, William Randolph B5F7 B7F7
Hirohito B3F10
Hitler, Adolph B3F4 B3F5-B3F6 B3F11-B3F12
holidays B1F1 B1F3 B1F6 B6F7 B7F3 B7F8
Hoover, Hebert B2F1-B2F2 B5F2 B5F7 B6F6
housing B6F5
Huerta, Victoriano B4F1 B4F4 B5F1 B6F3 B7F6
Hughes, Charles Evan B5F4-B5F5 B5F7 B6F7
Illinois B1F3 B1F7 B4F5 B5F4 B6F2 B6F7 B7F5-B7F6 B7F9
immigration B1F8 B4F3 B6F6 B7F8
industry (general) B2F1 B2F6 B3F9-B3F10 B4F1-B4F2 B4F4-B4F5 B6F3 B6F7 B7F2-B7F3 B7F6 B7F8-B7F9
inflation B2F7 B4F3
insurance B6F2
International Workers of the World B7F7
Iowa B1F4
Iraq B1F3-B1F4 B4F3
Ireland B4F5 B6F1 B6F6 B7F1 B7F7-B7F8
Italy B1F6 B1F8 B2F4-B2F5 B3F1 B3F6 B6F3 B6F7 B7F2 B7F4
Johnson, Hiram B5F3 B6F2-B6F3 B6F6 B7F2 B7F4
journalism B1F4 B1F6 B1F8 B4F3 B6F7 B7F2 B7F4
judicial system B1F1-B1F3 B1F5 B1F8 B2F2 B2F7 B6F7
Kellogg–Briand Pact B2F1-B2F3 B2F5
Ku Klux Klan B7F3
La Follette, Phil B4F1 B5F7 B6F1 B6F3-B6F4 B7F5-B7F6
labor B1F8 B2F2 B2F7 B4F2 B6F1 B7F7-B7F9
Labor Day B2F4
Landon, Alf B3F3
Latin America B2F1
lawyers B1F2
League of Nations B1F2-B1F7 B2F1-B2F2 B2F4 B2F6 B3F3 B3F11 B4F2 B4F4 B5F3 B6F1 B6F4 B6F6-B7F1 B7F6-B7F9
Lindbergh, Charles B1F7 B2F3 B2F5 B2F7 B3F2
Lithuania B1F8
Locarno Treaties B1F2-B1F3
Lorimer, William B6F2
Lusitania B4F1
MacDonald, James Ramsay B2F3
Marconi B3F4
McCall, John T. B5F3
Memorial Day B2F3
Mexico B1F5 B1F8-B2F1 B4F4-B5F1 B5F3-B5F6 B6F5 B7F1
mining B3F1 B4F5 B5F4-B5F5 B6F2 B6F7-B7F2 B7F4 B7F6-B7F8
Monroe Doctrine B4F5 B7F1
Montenegro B5F4
Moses, George H. B2F1
motion pictures B2F3 B3F1 B3F4 B7F2 B7F6
Mussolini, Benito B1F4 B3F3 B6F7
national debt B3F3
National Recovery Administration B2F7
nature B1F6 B3F3
navy B1F7-B2F5 B5F3 B6F6 B7F4 B7F7-B7F8
Nazis B3F11-B3F12
New Deal B3F1
New Jersey B5F7
New York (State) B5F4 B7F3-B7F5
New York City B1F3 B2F7 B5F5 B7F3
Nicaragua B1F7
Obregon, Alvaro B2F1
oil B1F3 B2F3 B4F2-B4F3 B4F5 B5F7 B6F6 B7F6-B7F7
Olympics B3F3
organized crime B2F7 B4F4 B6F7 B7F2 B7F8
Panama B4F4
Panama Canal B1F7 B2F1 B7F8
Parker, Alton B5F4
passenger ships B1F2
peace B2F2 B4F5 B5F4-B5F5 B5F7 B6F6 B7F6 B7F8
Pennsylvania B7F5
Piłsudski, Józef B1F4
Platt, T.C. B4F4
Poland B1F4 B1F8 B3F6 B3F11 B5F2 B6F2 B6F4
politics B1F3 B1F8-B2F1 B6F4 B6F6 B7F6
Progressivism B4F5 B7F1
Prohibition B1F2 B1F6 B2F4 B2F7 B5F2 B5F4 B6F1-B6F2 B6F4-B6F5 B6F7-B7F3 B7F6
prosperity B1F3
radio B1F3-B1F4 B3F4
railroad industry B2F2 B5F2 B6F2-B6F3 B7F1 B7F4 B7F6-B7F8
religion B1F6 B3F5 B4F3
Republican Party B1F5 B2F1 B2F7-B3F1 B3F3 B3F11 B4F3 B4F5 B5F3-B5F6 B6F3-B6F6 B7F1-B7F2 B7F6-B7F8
Rockefeller, John D., Jr. B2F2
Romania B1F8 B5F5
Roosevelt, Franklin D. B3F1 B3F3 B3F7-B3F10 B3F12 B4F3-B4F4
Roosevelt, Theodore B1F1 B4F4 B5F1-B5F2 B5F4-B6F2 B6F6 B7F3
rural free delivery B6F4
Russia B1F6-B1F7 B2F3 B2F6 B3F8 B4F2 B4F4 B5F1-B5F2 B5F5 B6F1 B6F3-B6F4 B7F2 B7F5 B7F7-B7F8
San Francisco Earthquake B5F4
science B1F6
shipping industry B4F1 B7F8
Sims, William B5F6
Sinclair, Harry B1F7-B1F8
Sinclair, Upton B3F1
Smith, Al B1F8 B2F1 B5F2 B6F7 B7F4
South Africa B5F4